THOMAS MAIER Software Engineer

☐ contact@thomas-maier.net

% +49 176 21989728

Stuttgart, Germany

TOP SKILLS

- Software Development
- Cloud Services
- Container/VM Orchestration
- · DevOps, CI/CD, SRE, GitOps
- UN*X Operating Systems
- Networking, IT-Security
- · Teaching, Training

FAVORITE TECHNOLOGIES

- Golang
- Java
- Spring Boot
- Python
- C/C++
- Shell Scripting
- JavaScript
- Swift
- PHP
- Docker
- Docker Swarm
- Kubernetes
- Helm
- Flux CD
- AWS
- GCP
- Terraform
- Ansible
- GitLab
- GitHub
- Debian derivatives
- RedHat derivatives
- SUSE derivatives
- Linux/Kernel development
- Immutable Linux

SUMMARY

A passionate Software Engineer with a broad spectrum of knowledge. Over 10 years of experience, mainly focused on the development, deployment and management of complex, service-oriented applications.

Engaged in scientific projects and active lecturer in university environment.

Loves to help Developers/Teams to reach their goals and actively contributes to Open Source projects.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, Leomedia GmbH

2020 - current

- Responsible for core platform development and DevOps for the main product leoticket (White-label Event Ticketing)
- Microservice development for leoticket
- Consultant work (Cloud services, Microservice design and development, Training)

Golang Spring Boot AWS Kubernetes Flux GitOps
GitLab CI/CD Python Terraform

Lecturer/Academic Staff, Stuttgart Media University

2020 - current

- Lecturing mainly about Cloud Services, IoT and Embedded Systems in project-oriented setups
 - 143303A Embedded Systems (Masters)
 - 113466A Cloud-Services and Internet of Things (Bachelors)
 - 119316A Mobile Application Development 2 (Bachelors)
 - 113105A Software-Entwicklung 1 (Bachelors)
- Scientific projects in the context of Cloud Services
- Operation and Management of on-premise GitLab and other software services for faculty

AWS GCP IoT Golang Java Terraform

GitLab Ops Rancher Docker RP2040 Swift

Senior Software Engineer, Leomedia GmbH

2018 - 2020

- Responsible for DevOps and Automations for Docker Swarm and Galera Clusters
- Consultant work (Service development in the context of high-quality car visualizations)
- Technical project management for B2B services

Docker Swarm MariaDB Galera GitLab CI/CD Spring Boot
Linux Networking IT-Security Web Components
Three.js Shell Scripting Ansible

LANGUAGES

German: NativeEnglish: Advanced

EDUCATION

M. Sc. Computer Sc. and Media 2013, Stuttgart Media University

B. Sc. Medieninformatik2011, Stuttgart Media University

Advanced technical college certificate 2007, Kolping-Kolleg Rottenburg

Trained electrician, Dual vocational training 2005, Gewerbl. Schule Tübingen

OTHER INTERESTS

- · Embedded Systems
- · CAD, EDA
- Audio technology
- Outdoor sports

Lecturer/Academic Staff, Stuttgart Media University

2013 - 2020

- Lecturing about Embedded Systems and Networking in project-oriented setups
 - 143303A Embedded Systems (Masters)
 - 113459A Praktikum Rechnernetze (Firewalls and VPN's, Bachelors)
- Scientific work in the context of Linux, Networking and Virtualization

Linux Docker Netfilter OpenVPN

IPSec Atmega328P

IT Ops Engineer, Leomedia GmbH

2013 - 2018

- Responsible for Operation and Management of internal software services
- Technical project management for B2B services
- Docker Swarm Cluster design and deployment

Docker Swarm GitLab Jenkins Shell Scripting

Linux Networking IT-Security

Software Development student, Leomedia GmbH

2009 - 2013

- Working student
- · Prototype development for various Web and Mobile Applications

Java PHP Linux Objective-C Shell Scripting

Software Development student, ETAS GmbH

2009 - 2011

- Integrated work experience / Internship
- Bachelors Thesis
- Working student

Apache Solr PHP Linux RTOS Networking

PRIVATE PROJECTS

C K4wd

kubectl port-forward on steroids.

(RUC

TCP-based protocol, client library and tools to render frames remotely on Pimoroni's space Unicorns.

ncloud-k3s

Terraform-based multi-node K3s deployment on Hetzner Cloud infrastructure with a focus on simplicity.

volmex

Docker volume driver that implements a pre-mount hook for arbitrary commands.